

# **Blessing Ogoh Onyowoicho**

I am a talented Software Developer with above 3 years experience with building scalable, responsive and accessible web and desktop applications. Using analysis, design and programming, I develop solutions users with special needs can easily navigate. Ultimately, helping companies reach more customers and generate more profit.

## **Personal Information**

234-708-210-7805

ogoh\_blessing@yahoo.com



https://blaire.vercel.app

https://github.com/bl-aire



https://www.linkedin.com/in/ogoh-blessing/

# **Experience**

## Software Developer

JupyterHub | 2022 - Present

- Evaluted JupyterHub's user-interface using WAVE accessibility testing tool.
- Improved JupyterHub's accessibility using HTML, CSS and Bootstrap.
- Automated accessibility testing using Playwright.

#### ServiceNow Developer

## ERS | 2022

Designed and developed Emergency Response Service with a team of talented developer. ERS
provides a means to curb Nigeria's problem of a lack of a means to get help from medical or
security teams during emergencies.

## Mobile Web Developer

Google Africa Developer Schoolarship | 2021-2022

• Developed responsive and accessible applications with HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Angular.

#### Education

# University of Ilorin, Kwara state Bachelor of Science in Physiology

2014 - 2018

#### Skills

- HTML, CSS and Javascript/TypeScript
- Bootstrap, Angular and REST API usage
- Accessibility tools (WAVE, axe DevTools, assistive technologies)